Your Highness!
What's the meaning of this,
Lieutenant General Safida?
You're the high commander
of the Northern Garrison.
Why were you the first to flee?
Many soldiers are still in
the process of retreating!
The commanding officer's safety
is the highest priority.
I see. You're right.
We'll need you to be present at the
military tribunal when this is over.
You mustn't die, Solork.
There's something I have to tell you.
Ghost Hunter
Ideally,
we would've been able to defend the
barricades without having to retreat.
Even if the enemy attacked again
after they pulled back,
we could have bought half or even a full day.
Is that loss of a day going to prove fatal?
Not particularly.
However,
from now on, it depends on the enemy.
What will the Holy Aldera Army do,
now that they've actually fought us?
Let's wait and see.
Ryttsah!
Such lovely weather!
Jean, a message from our allies
in the mountains.
Syoo!
That's your brother, all right.
He's selected exactly the information I want.
And this is the most interesting bit:
A member of the Igsem family,
famed for its swordplay, is in that army.
Yes.
Even my brother referred to
her skills as "extraordinary."
She probably is truly extraordinary, then.
It may be thanks to her
that we're stuck here.
I'm sorry.
It's my fault they died.
No need to apologize.
Ikta apologized to me first.
I would have you test my faith as well.
You may cut off both my arms.
But please let me keep them
for the duration of this battle,
so that I may wield a sword!
S...
Stop it...
Stop it, please!
That's not right!
If you do that, then...
Then...
how am I supposed to forgive myself?
I didn't want to kill anyone!
I didn't want to kill people
from my own country!
I had no idea that simply becoming a soldier
meant you had to fight so many battles
without any just cause...
That's the responsibility of the person
who gave the orders,
Sergeant Major Mitcalif.
All the people you think you killed
were actually killed by me.
You did your job splendidly.
There's no reason you should
be blamed for anything.
But doesn't that mean
you'll be punished by God?
Don't worry.
I have a commanding officer, too.
Once we're all dead, he can
actually do some work for once.
So, change of subject...
Have you two seen First Lieutenant Ikta?
He should just sleep in his own tent.
He insisted on sleeping on straw today.
Something they gave their lives to protect...
You don't see it as a platitude
or formality either, do you?
Ikta, you boor.
If you were going to sleep somewhere,
you could have slept in my bed.
Wh-What did you say—
Captain Sazaluf,
the enemy's on the move!
They're here, huh?
Another unit of enemies has split off
for the bypass on the right.
Approximately 500 mounted units.
But half of the horses have two riders:
a cavalryman and an infantryman behind him.
Clever.
Yeah.
It's a lot faster than just
having the infantry walk.
Let's send a force to intercept.
It's obvious they're trying to
make us split our forces,
but we can only play along.
So, the question is who we send.
Torway and I will handle it.
It can be Torway and myself as well.
I'll go.
Well, my reason is pretty sad,
but hear me out.
To be honest, this battle's been beyond
my ability to handle for a while now.
If I'm left in charge here,
I'm not sure I can make the right calls.
And actually, First Lieutenant Ikta
and First Lieutenant Yatorishino,
I think it's a bad idea for
you two to leave this place.
If occupying a fort and fighting a textbook
war of attrition is all that's needed,
even I can handle that.
Makes me a failure as a commanding officer,
but I'm the best man for this.
Please let me go.
All right.
I'll leave you to handle the enemies
on the bypass route,
but please take Torway and his men.
You sure?
They're our air rifle unit.
That's exactly why.
You can do it, right, Torway?
Yeah.
It's going to be tough for a while,
but if you follow Ikkun and
Yatori-san, it'll be fine.
Yeah.
Hang in there.
Take care of the western fort, okay?
Yeah.
He's really changed.
He's standing up straighter.
It's like he's grown up.
Yes.
He's a lot different than me.
Yes?
Matthew-san.
Anything that's taboo in the Aldera religion
would be taboo for the Aldera Army, right?
Of course—
Hey!
It's a beautiful day for a trip
through the sky, right, Miara?
If you've got time to talk,
finish this up already!
Syah!
A force of over a hundred
is heading for the west.
I've written that down!
Now let's get back to the surface.
As fast as we can!
Right now!
We can stay up here a for a bit, right?
The general finally gave me the okay.
As far as anyone else will be told,
I'm doing this on my own, though.
L-Look, sir!
That accursed thing!
Oh, what is that?!
Damn that Kioka kid!
I'll arrest him immediately!
These little acts aren't for me.
You don't seem terribly happy
about this, either.
It's the Kiokans who feel it's acceptable
to break the commandments
to ensure victory.
But it's also true that you can't win a fight
if you're only trying to look good for God.
I didn't expect them to send a blimp.
Perhaps the Alderan commander
is more flexible than we thought.
Attention!
That's just a recon vessel.
Don't spend all your time
staring up into the sky at it.
We need to look at reality,
and at the future.
Listen, we need to buy
a minimum of seven days
to support the retreat.
As you can see,
the fire we set in the forest
is starting to burn out.
The enemy will come through
the burnt-out parts to attack.
Which means it's clear
what we have to do, right?
First, restore the wall of flame.
Second, repel the enemies as they attack.
That's right.
From now on, we'll need to maintain
an adaptive, mobile defense.
I'll be sending a number of you
to the appropriate places
depending on where the fire's burnt out
and what the enemy does.
We just keep that up for seven days.
To pull this off, we just need one thing:
a scientific stance from you.
For the next seven days,
you must be lazy in the right way.
You must work when it's time to work,
and rest when it's time to rest.
And seven days later,
when our mission is complete,
we'll be heading south for our own retreat.
I don't doubt that future at all.
As of this moment,
I am initiating the mobile defense operation!
Bypass Route - Western Fortress
Wow, that's quite the barrier.
Which means... I guess we go to sleep.
No, wait, you big dummy!
It doesn't look like we could knock
that out at night or by surprise.
We've got the plan Jean gave us, too.
You giant Udo tree!
How many times do I have to tell you
not to pick people up for no reason?
So they're finally here, huh?
Doesn't look like
they'll attack tonight, though.
They'll attack during the day,
when they can use their air rifles.
Meraize, right?
What's going on with the air mortars?
We brought them down from the mountains,
but we only have six.
Forgive us.
Well done.
Okay, pour on the oil!
Yeah, at this rate it'll just
be another five minutes...
Everyone, stop work and focus to our front!
Fire!
So, it's the third day of the mission,
and our first enemy encounter?
That about matches my expectations.
Order Matthew's platoon
to take a four-hour rest.
Yatori will take over for him.
Roger.
A report from the rear.
The blimp has been seen
near the eastern forest path.
The blimp again?
And at the east?
Yes.
There are 300 cavalry below it,
running across the same area again and again.
The same area?
I don't know why.
Nana,
is there possibly an eastern route
they could take to get around?
No, I guarantee there isn't.
What are they doing, then?
Enemy unit withdrawing!
They're pretty passive.
With 800 men, they could afford
to be a little more bold.
What are they waiting for?
Captain,
I want to deploy my platoon to the rear.
May I have permission?
The rear?
Why?
It can't be—
The Imperial Army's back is wide open.
When our rifle attack disorients them,
our allies will charge.
Line up on the ridge and prepare to fire!
Go!
The red-haired Igsem woman.
Two blades...
This isn't the weapon I should be holding.
We will open fire now.
Aim, fire!
An ambush?
Keep firing!
The enemy is bunched up!
We can win!
The third day after you
arrive at the fortress,
or perhaps the fourth day,
Kala Karm will attack the rear
while the sun is up.
But we haven't seen Kala Karm...
Not once, no.
That's just because this area
makes it difficult to attack.
But...
That's right!
The western fortress is different!
This is the chance they've been waiting for.
They'll attack from the rear
using their air rifles.
How should my unit handle them?
First, turn the chess board around.
If you were the Kala Karm commander,
how would you attack the fortress?
By looking for a place around
150 meters from the fortress,
where I could easily set up a firing line.
Just keep asking yourself that question.
If the enemy attacked like that,
how would you deal with them?
I dealt with them like this, Ikkun!
All forces, retreat!
The enemy is retreating.
I won't let a single one escape.
You're kidding me.
They took out Kala Karm?
We don't have a choice. We'll attack.
The enemy's split their forces
to set that ambush.
I think they'll come right back, though!
So we knock out the fortress right now!
They're here!
Good! Everyone, intercept!
Are the air mortars ready?
The battle at the fort continues,
but they say there's no risk
of falling right now.
Use the light signals to
tell them they did well.
And that after three more days of defending,
they are to retreat.
Yes, sir.
I see...
Torway pulled it off, huh?
Yatori Platoon has finished replenishing
the fires in sector two on the west side.
Hey, Yatori.
Good work.
I figured that would be the case,
so I brought some for you.
I see.
So Torway did it.
Yeah.
Looks like he managed to
deal with the Ghosts.
Did he take out the commander?
I don't know.
His report said they were
almost entirely wiped out.
But I assume you
wanted revenge for Warrant Officer Deinkun?
That's right.
Either way, Torway wins.
This time.
No.
It may be past the time to
talk about winning and losing.
The power of the air rifles is overwhelming.
Has the age of the sword already passed?
From Igsem of the Sword
to Remeon of the Gun.
The star of the battlefield changes.
I don't think that's a bad thing
for you, though.
You bear too many burdens right now.
If I told you everything I'd done
since I joined the military
was to make the burden on you lighter,
would you get mad?
If I can have that as a goal,
maybe I can forgive myself...
For breaking my promise with my mom
and becoming a soldier.
I won't get mad.
But, even if that's true, I...
There's still some time.
Use it all to worry about the future.
I'll help make it so your conclusion
leads to a better future.
Until the day comes when
you can hold your head high
and be proud of who you are,
I will be by your side.
Mobile Defense Operation - 6th Day
Enemy reinforcements?
They took a very long way around the east,
and even our allies on the mountain
couldn't see them.
The east side of the forest...
That's where that blimp was flying.
There are supposedly six wagons
pulling something big.
Something big?
Have our allies find out
what it is immediately!
Yes, sir!
Hey!
You did well to make it here by sunset.
Begin loading!
Inject sun energy!
All cannons are ready to fire!
Fire!
What was that noise?
It was too loud to be mortars!
Ikta, are those...
The sound of horses?
But that way is...
Explosive cannons!
What's a explosive cannon?
It's a new weapon the Kioka military has
that detonates compressed sun energy
to propel a cannon shell.
It should be something the Holy Army of
Aldera despises even more than blimps.
Those explosive cannons can destroy
the barricades from beyond the flames.
Oh! So, that was it?!
I finally get why the cavalry kept running
in the same spot under the blimp!
They were training!
They used the blimp to record
the paths through the forest,
and built an obstacle course to mimic it.
Then they memorized the way to
break through the wall of flames!
They got us!
So the explosive cannons
that were brought to Aldera,
and never saw any use,
are now used like this...
But the general is going to be
very upset with you again.
Exkyaazy!
I'll think of an excuse later.
Come, it's time to make the Empire pay
for keeping us sitting here.
All forces, to the west!
The Imperial Army's desperate attempt
to maintain the firewall
was broken by the
Unsleeping, Shining Officer.
There were less than two days left
until the rear guard could retreat.
Next time: "In a Twilight Empire."
In a Twilight Empire